Ariel Aguirre

 ♥ Buenos Aires, Argentina
 ☑ ariedro@gmail.com
 Ø ariedro.dev
 in ariedro
 ♠ ariedro

About me

I'm a software developer with a strong background in web applications, covering both back-end and front-end development, with experience in cloud technologies and blockchain integrations.

Also I enjoy exploring topics like game programming, graphics, networking, and low-level programming.

I'm always open to expanding my horizons and learning new things.

Experience

Altoros 🗹 2021 – 2024

Full Stack Software Developer

- Provided technical leadership, roadmap planning and guidance to development teams
- Contributed to the development and migration of projects from monolithic cores to modern microservices, working on architecture design and coding implementation
- Improved projects security and stability by patching vulnerabilities and bug fixes, as well as updating and maintaining servers infrastructure

Personal Flow 🗹 2020 – 2021

Back End Software Developer

- Managed a microservices-based system and participated in the migration of it to a modern infrastructure
- o Developed tools to improve and extend the CI and deployment control
- o Contributed to support and issue fixing of back-end API web services

Atix Labs (now part of Globant)

2018 - 2020

Full Stack Software Developer

- Contributed to the development of various MVP web applications, overseeing front-end and back-end design and implementation, as well as database schema design
- Worked on crypto DeFi apps with smart contract integrations, as well as encryption schemes for file sharing
- Developed React Native applications for Android and iOS front-ends

Education

University of Buenos Aires Z

2016 - In progress

Software Engineering

Technologies

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Golang, HTML, CSS, Bash, SQL, Python, C

Frameworks: Node.js, React, Nest, Meteor, Sails.js, React Native Database Management: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firestore, SQLite

Cloud Related: Docker, AWS, Google Cloud Platform, nginx

Programming Related: REST, Git, Express.js, Fastify, GraphQL, Blockchain

Metodologies: Agile, Scrum, TDD, Kanban

Languages

English: Fluent
Spanish: Native